pipefy.com 2019-07-15

# Privacy Policy | Pipefy

This Privacy Policy describes Pipefy’s policies and procedures on the collection, use and disclosure of your information when you use the Pipefy Service. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our terms of service. By accessing or using the Service, you agree to this Privacy Policy. Information We Collect and Use

### Information We Collect and Use

Pipefy uses information we collect to operate, maintain and provide you the features and functionality of the Service, to analyze how the Service is used, diagnose service or technical problems, maintain security, personalize content, remember information to help you efficiently access your account, monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns, and track Content and users as necessary to comply with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act and other applicable laws.

**Information You Provide:  **You provide us information about yourself, such as your name and e-mail address, if you register for an account with the Service, including by connecting with the Service via a third-party service, or by “following,” “becoming a fan,” adding the Pipefy application, etc., on a third party website or network. Your name, email address and other information you choose to provide on the Service will be viewable and discoverable by other users, in accordance with your settings on the Service. We may use your email address to send you Service-related notices (including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail). We may also use your contact information to send you marketing messages. If you don’t want to receive these messages, you can opt out by following the instructions in the message. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses. If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to the Service, we will ask you for that person’s email address and automatically send an email invitation. Pipefy stores this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our invitation service.

**Content:**  You also provide us non personal information in Content you post to the Service. Your Content and metadata about your Content may be viewed by other users in accordance with your settings on the Service. Pipefy can, but has no obligation, to monitor your Content you post on the Service. We can remove any information you post for any reason or no reason. Unless Content is made viewable in accordance with your settings on the Service, Pipefy and Pipefy employees will not view your Content except: (i) to maintain, provide or improve the Service; (ii) to help you and resolve your support requests; or (iii) as Pipefy believes, in its sole opinion, is necessary to comply with or avoid the violation of applicable law or regulation or to cooperate with law enforcement.

**Cookies:**  When you use the Service, we may send one or more “cookies” – a small data file – to your computer to uniquely identify your browser and let Pipefy help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may convey anonymous information about how you browse the Service to us. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser so that it can be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Service. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

**Log Files:**  When you use the Service, our servers automatically record certain information sent by your web browser. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, mobile carrier, and other such information.

**Clear Gifs Information:**  When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting and make Pipefy better for our users.

**Geo-Location Information:**  When you use the Service by or through a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store “location data,” which may include GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. Location data may convey information about how you browse the Service to us. Location data does not collect or share any personally identifiable information about you. Location data may be used in conjunction with personally identifiable information. Some features of the Service, particularly location-based services, may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled.

**Device Identifiers:**  When you access the Service by or through a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store one or more “device identifiers.” Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your mobile device, which uniquely identify your mobile device and are used to enhance the Service. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device’s operating system or other software, or data sent to the device by us. A device identifier may convey information about how you use the Service to us. A device identifier does not collect or share any personally identifiable information about you. A device identifier may be used in conjunction with personally identifiable information. A device identifier may remain persistently on your device, to help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Service. Some features of the Service may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers are impaired or disabled. Pipefy may access, collect and/or store device identifiers upon enabling Pipefy’s Services.

**Third Party Tools:  **Pipefy uses third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, to help understand use of the Service. Many of these tools collect the information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address. These analytics tools also receive this information and their use of it is governed by their privacy policy.

### How We Share Your Information

**Your Use** : We will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Service according to the preferences you set in your account. Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want others to know about you. Please consider carefully what information you disclose in your profile page and your desired level of anonymity. You can review and revise your profile information at any time. We may also share or disclose your information with your consent, for example, if you use a third party application to access your account (see below).

**Service Providers, Business Partners, and Others** : Pipefy may (i) share your contact information with our trusted business partners, who may reach out to you regarding products or services that may be relevant to you; and (ii) share your personally identifiable information with other third parties for the purpose of providing the Service to you. If we do this, such business partners and other third parties will be bound by obligations to keep your information confidential. We may also store personal information in locations outside the direct control of Pipefy (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

**Business Transfers:**  As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customers, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

**Third Party Services:**  We may share your information with a third party application with your consent, for example when you choose to access our Services through such an application. We are not responsible for what those parties do with your information, so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy acceptable to you.

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests and  Protection of Pipefy’s Rights:** Pipefy may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Pipefy’s rights or property.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may disclose your non-private, aggregated, or otherwise non-personally identifiable information, such as anonymous usage data, platform types, etc., with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain Pipefy Services.

### How We Protect Your Information

The security of your information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) as part of our service, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Pipefy uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information, once we receive it. For example, we continuously and regularly back up your data to help prevent data loss and aid in data recovery. We also guard against common web attack vectors, host data in secure SAS 70 audited data centers, and implement firewalls and access restrictions on our servers to secure our network and better protect your information. No method of electronic transmission of storage is 100% secure, however, and we cannot ensure or warrant the absolute security of any information you transmit or store in the Service.

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Pipefy will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

### Your Choices About Your Information

You have the right to:

  * Request an accounting of all personal information that we possess that pertains to you in an electronically portable format (e.g., electronic copies of information attached to an email).
  * Request that we change any personal information that pertains to you.
  * Request that we delete any personal information that pertains to you.

To request an accounting of your personal information, a change to your personal information, or deletion of your personal information, [contact us](https://app.pipefy.com/public/form/ONITydQF).

If you have a complaint about our use or processing of your personal information, you have a right to lodge a complaint with a national Data Protection Authority.  Each European Union member nation has established its own Data Protection Authority; you can find out about the Data Protection Authority in your country [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

### Right to withdraw consent

In case you have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your Personal Data, you have the right to fully or partly withdraw your consent. To withdraw your consent, please [contact us](https://app.pipefy.com/public/form/ONITydQF).

Once we have received notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will no longer process your information for the purpose(s) to which you originally consented unless there are compelling legitimate grounds for further processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

In case we processed your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time, in which case we will no longer process your Personal Data for such marketing purposes.

### Pipefy Blog & Community

Our Service offers publicly accessible community services including blogs, and forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Your posts may remain even after you cancel your account.

### Geographic Location

We offer the service in several geographic regions.  We define a geographical region as the location where a user is located.

_Users Within the United States_

For users within the United States, we process data in data centers located in the United States.  We have adopted reasonable physical, technical, and organizational safeguards against accidental, unauthorized, or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, disclosure, access, use, or processing of user data in our possession.  We comply with state and federal laws governing the protection of personal information.

_Users Within the European Union_

For users within the European Union, we transfer data from the European Union to data centers located in the United States for processing.  Such processing is performed in accordance with Regulation 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of April 27, 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and free movement of such data, known as the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).  This includes the imposition of required safeguards with respect to accidental, unauthorized or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, disclosure, access, use or processing of data.  Transfers of European Union user data to processors in the United States are made in accordance with the Standard Contractual Clauses applicable pursuant to the GDPR.

_Users in Other Regions_

For users not within the United States or the European Union, we transfer data from such regions to the United States for processing. For such users, we have adopted reasonable physical, technical, and organizational safeguards against accidental, unauthorized, or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, disclosure, access, use, or processing of user data in our possession that substantially mirror protections available to users located within the United States.

### Grounds for using your personal information

We rely on the following legal grounds to process your personal information, namely:

Performance of a contract – We need to collect and use your personal information to perform our agreement with you to deliver the Service as described in this Privacy Policy.

Consent – We may use or disclose some of your personal information such as precise location information or collect cookies as described in this Privacy Policy subject to your consent.

Legitimate interests – We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests to improve our products and services and the content on our Services. Consistent with our legitimate interests and any choices that we offer or consents that may be required under applicable laws, we may use technical information as described in this Privacy Policy and use personal information for our marketing purposes.

### Retention and Deletion

We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected and processed, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, accounting or reporting requirements.

In some circumstances, we may anonymize your personal information so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case it is no longer personal data.

It is our policy to retain personal information for up to 6 months once such personal information is no longer necessary to deliver the Service and to delete such personal information thereafter.  This means that, if you close your account with us, we will delete personal information associated with your account after no more than 6 months.

Regarding other types of information we collect as described in this policy (Cookies, Log Files, Geo-Location Information, Device Identifiers), it is our policy to retain such personal information for up to 6 months and to delete such personal information thereafter.

### Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. Contact Us If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#daaaa8b3acbbb9a39aaab3aabfbca3f4b9b5b7).

### About Pipefy

Pipefy is based in the United States at 10 Jackson St, San Francisco, CA 94110

Users in the United States and regions other than the EU can contact us at the above address.

The Company has appointed as its representative pursuant to article 27 of the GDPR the French law firm Foley Hoag AARPI, Avocats au Barreau de Paris, 153 rue du Faubourg Saint Honoré, 75008 Paris, France.

Last updated: October 25, 2018.
